bidsketch.com 2019-05-02

# Privacy

_Last revised: May 22, 2018_

**CONTENT**

  1. **Introduction** : who we are and why you need to read this Privacy Policy 

  2. **Definitions** : what is defined as personal information and what is not 

  3. **What information is collected, how it is used and when it is shared** : type of information we collect about you, how and why we use it, and under what circumstances your information may be shared with others 

  4. **Security** : where we store your information and how we protect it 

  5. **Location of servers** : we store your information on US servers 

  6. **For users from EU - Your rights with regard to information we collect about you** : You certain rights with regard to management of your Personal Information including the right to modify or delete information from our servers or to move your information from our servers to another company’s server 

  7. **Data Retention** : how long we may store your information for 

  8. **Do not track disclosure**

  9. **Links to third-party web sites** : our disclaimer with regard to third-party web links found via the Service and such third-party websites’ privacy policy practices 

  10. **Children’s privacy** : we do not collect information from persons under the age of 18 

  11. **Compliance with laws** : Our Privacy Policy complies with the strictest privacy protection laws in the world so you have peace of mind 

  12. **Changes to privacy policy** : we may make changes to this Privacy Policy; we will notify you if any such changes occur; your continued use of the Service will constitute your consent to 

  13. **Contact us** : our contact information 

### 1\. INTRODUCTION

Your privacy and the security of your personal information are very important to us. This Privacy Policy is incorporated into and made part of our Terms of Service located at [www.bidsketch.com/terms](https://www.bidsketch.com/terms/). This Privacy Policy describes how Earthlingsoft, LLC DBA Bidsketch, a limited liability company governed by the laws of the State of Oregon (“Bidsketch,“ "us," "we," or "our"), collects, stores, uses your information, under what circumstances it might share or disclose it and how your information is being stored and protected. It is vital that you read this Privacy Policy carefully before using [www.bidsketch.com](https://www.bidsketch.com/) website ("Service") operated by Bidsketch. The Service is a platform where users of the Service may execute legal instruments using their electronic signatures. 

By using the Service, you consent to Bidsketch’s practices of collecting, storing, using, sharing, disclosing, and protecting your personal information. If you agree to consent to this Privacy Policy on behalf of an entity, "you," "your," or “yours” will refer and apply to that entity. If you do not agree with and consent to all the practices described in this Privacy Policy, please do not register for an account and discontinue using the Service. 

### 2\. INTRODUCTION

  * **“Personal Information”** means any information that identifies or can be used to identify or contact a person if used combined together with other pieces of information. Such Personal Information may include, but is not limited to, a name, identification number, an online identifier, mailing or billing address, email address, telephone number, photo, signature, Internet Protocol (“IP”) address location data, cookie identifier, date of birth, billing or credit/debit card information, or one or more factors specific to physical, physiological, genetic, mental, economic, cultural or social identity of a person. 

  * **“Non-Personal Information”** means information that cannot be used to identify or contact a person. Such Non-Personal Information may include, but is not limited to, user’s browser type, browser version, operating system, files viewed, webpages visited, time and date of user’s visit, time spent on each webpage and other anonymous statistical data. 

  * **“Content”** means any information, text, documents, graphics, videos, or other materials uploaded, posted, displayed, shared and otherwise made available on or through the Service. 

  * All terms not defined in this Privacy Policy are defined in our Terms of Service found at [www.Bidsketch.com/terms](https://www.bidsketch.com/terms/). 

### 3\. WHAT INFORMATION IS COLLECTED, HOW IT IS USED AND WHEN IT IS SHARED 

We collect both Personal Information and Non-Personal Information about you. Here is what information we collect about you, how and why we use it, and under what circumstances your information may be shared with others: 

  * **Account Registration.** Upon registering for an account, we ask you to provide your full name, email address, and create a password. We collect this information for the purpose of providing you with the Service, servicing your Subscription, identifying you as a user, sending you updates about our Terms of Service, Privacy Policy or other legal notices and marketing offers, or responding to your requests/inquiries. 

  * **Your Content.** Any information, text, documents, comment you leave for any third party inside any document, graphics, videos, audio files, or other materials uploaded, posted, displayed, shared and otherwise made available by you on or through the Service will be collected and stored by us for the purpose of providing you with the Service or servicing your Subscription. This includes any information you fill out inside any document (for example, when you are asked to fill out and sign an agreement). Your Content is not shared with anyone except those you voluntarily decide to share it with. You are solely responsible for your Content. You assume all risks associated with the use and sharing of your Content, including any reliance on its accuracy, completeness or usefulness by others, or any disclosure of your Content that makes you or any third party personally identifiable. 

  * **Submission of Suggestions and Feedback.** If you provide us with any suggestions or feedback about the Service (“Suggestions”), you will automatically assign to us all rights to the Suggestions and agree that we shall have the right to use such Suggestions and related information in any manner we deem appropriate. We will treat any Suggestions you provide to us as non-confidential and non-proprietary. You agree that you will not submit to us any information or ideas that you consider to be confidential or proprietary. 

  * **Your Financial Data.** We may employ third-party service providers to facilitate the provision of the Service. Such third-party service providers will have access to your Personal Information only to perform specific tasks on our behalf and are obligated not to disclose or use your Personal Information for any other purpose. One of such third-party service providers that we work with is Authorize.Net (a third party payment processing company). It handles payment operations for us. When you want to pay for your Subscription, you will be asked to provide billing information including full name, address, state, zip or postal code, telephone number, a valid credit or debit card number, and its expiration date and CVV number. We collect such pieces of information and forward it to Authorize.Net. Authorize.Net is responsible for processing and storing your financial data. If you wish to know how your financial data is processed and stored, please read Authorize.Net’s privacy policy located at [https://www.authorize.net/company/privacy](https://www.authorize.net/company/privacy/). On our end, we are only able to see and store your billing address and telephone number that will be used to contact you in case there is a billing issue. 

  * **Cookie Identifiers.** “Cookies” are small files created by websites a user visits. They are designed to hold a modest amount of data specific to a particular user and website, and can be accessed either by a web server or such user’s computer. Cookies are a convenient way to carry information from one session on a website to another, or between sessions on related websites, without having to burden a server machine with massive amounts of data storage. Storing the data on the server without using Cookies would also be problematic because it would be difficult to retrieve a particular user's information without requiring a login on each visit to the website. If there is a large amount of information to store, then a Cookie can simply be used as a means to identify a given user so that further related information can be looked up on a server-side database. For example, the first time a user visits a site he/she may choose a username, which is stored in the Cookie, and then provide data such as password, name, address, preferred font size, and so on. This information would all be stored in a database using the username as a key. Subsequently when the site is revisited the server will read the cookie to find the username, and then retrieve all the user's information from the database without making the user to re-enter it. 

By using the Service, you agree that we may use session Cookies to enable the Service to keep track of your movement from webpage to webpage so you are not asked to re-sign in or enter the same information you have already provided (during an active browser session). Session Cookies are destroyed when the current browser window is closed. If you refuse the use the Cookies some features of the Service may not work or will be disabled. In order to ensure smooth operation of the Service, you must accept the use of Cookies. You may instruct your browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. The Help feature on most browsers provide information on how to accept cookies, disable cookies or to notify you when receiving a new cookie. 

  * **Google Analytics and Similar Analytics Tools.** Third party services such as Google Analytics and Kissmetrics help businesses and site owners analyze the traffic to their websites and mobile applications by collecting, monitoring and analyzing Non-Personal Information. 

Google Analytics works via a “page tag” or so-called “Google Analytics Tracking Code”, which is a snippet of JavaScript code. A website owner adds this code to every page of a website that he/she would like to track. When a website user visits the website (and Javascript is enabled), the tracking code runs in such user’s browser, collects user’s data, and sends it to a Google data collection server. Google Analytics may collect the following types of Non-Personal Information about how users use a website: date and time of visit, webpages visited, time spent on each webpage, referring web site details (such as the URI a user came through to arrive at this site), type of web browser, type of operating system, Flash version, screen resolution, and screen color processing ability, network location and IP address (IP address may be Personal and Non-Personal Information depending on whether it is anonymized or not). Google Analytics may also be used to such Non-Personal Information as: document downloads, clicks on links leading to external web sites, errors when users fill out forms, clicks on videos, scroll depth, interactions with site-specific widgets. Google’s latest version of Google Analytics (Universal Analytics) can be used to track mobile app activity, telephone conversations, point of sale transactions, and RFID or NFC sensor activity. Google Analytics does not collect any Personal Information from users of a website. 

We also share your email address, name and IP address with Kissmetrics to help us better analyze the traffic of the Service. 

By using the Service, you agree that we may use third party services such as Google Analytics and Kissmetrics to help us analyze the traffic to the Service. To learn more about how Google Analytics collects and processes your Non-Personal Information, please refer to Google’s privacy policy located at <https://policies.google.com/privacy>. 

  * **Facebook’s Remarketing Service.** Bidsketch uses Facebook’s remarketing services to show advertisements (also called interest-based advertising) to you on third party web sites after you have visited the Service. You can learn more about interest-based advertising from Facebook by visiting [www.facebook.com/help/164968693837950](https://www.facebook.com/help/164968693837950). To manage your ad setting or preferences, follow the instructions found here [www.facebook.com/about/ads/#568137493302217](https://www.facebook.com/about/ads/#568137493302217). Facebook adheres to the Self-Regulatory Principles for Online Behavioral Advertising established by the Digital Advertising Alliance (“DAA”). You can also opt-out from Facebook and other participating companies through the DAA in the USA [www.aboutads.info/choices/](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/), the DAA of Canada in Canada [www.youradchoices.ca](https://youradchoices.ca/) or the European Interactive Digital Advertising Alliance in Europe [www.youronlinechoices.eu](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/), or opt-out using your mobile device settings. For more information on the privacy practices of Facebook, please visit Facebook's Data Policy [www.facebook.com/privacy/explanation](https://www.facebook.com/privacy/explanation). 

  * **Email Marketing.** We and third-party email campaign service providers (Postmark, Drip, and Intercom) may use your email address to contact you with newsletters, marketing or promotional materials and other information that may be of interest to you. You may opt out of receiving any, or all, of these communications from us or our partner by following the unsubscribe links or instructions provided in any emails we or our partners send. To find out how Drip uses your email address, please follow this link: <https://www.drip.com/privacy>. For Postmark’s privacy policy, please refer to <https://postmarkapp.com/eu-privacy>. To find out more about Intercom’s privacy policy, please follow this link and click on privacy policy <https://www.intercom.com/terms-and-policies>. 

  * **Business Transfers or Bankruptcy.** We may sell, transfer or otherwise share some or all of our assets, including your Personal Information, in connection with a merger, acquisition, reorganization or sale of assets or in the event of bankruptcy. 

  * **Disclosures for Legal Purposes.** We may disclose your Personally Identifiable Information if required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to (i) comply with a legal obligation, (ii) protect and defend our rights or property, (iii) act in urgent circumstances to protect the personal safety of Service users or the public, or (iv) protect us from legal liability. 

  * **Use and Disclosure of Non-Personal Information.** We reserve the right to use and disclose Non-Personal Information for any purpose and to share it with any third party at our sole discretion. 

### 4\. SECURITY 

Your connection to Service is secure and encrypted using SSL (Secure Sockets Layer). This is the same level of encryption used by leading banks and government agencies. 

We host information about you in a secure server and cloud-based environment provided by Amazon.com, Inc. (“AWS”). AWS takes top security measures in order to ensure safe retention and storage of Personal Information. In order to read more about AWS’ security measures, please refer to <https://aws.amazon.com/compliance/data-center/controls/>. 

Despite these measures, however, you should know that we cannot fully eliminate security risks associated with your information. You are also responsible for helping us protect the security of your Personal Information. For instance, never give out your password, and remember to log out of your account after each session. 

### 5\. LOCATION OF SERVERS 

If you are located outside the United States and choose to use the Service, please note that we will store information about you including your Content on servers located in the United States. 

### 6\. FOR USERS FROM EU: YOUR RIGHTS WITH REGARD TO INFORMATION WE COLLECT ABOUT YOU 

If you are accessing the Service from one of EU Member States, you have the following rights with regard to information about you: 

  * the right to be informed about what kind of Personal Information about you is collected, stored, processed and disclosed by us; therefore, we have compiled this Privacy Policy for you; 

  * the right of access (you can request us to provide you verbally or in writing with the Personal Information and Non-Personal Information that we store about you and we have a month to respond to your request); 

  * the right to rectify any Personal Information that is inaccurate; 

  * the right to erasure (some conditions apply, see Section 7 below); 

  * the right to restrict processing your Personal Information, however, if you restrict us from processing a part of Personal Information that is essential to our provision of the Service, you may be asked to terminate your account and stop using the Service; 

  * the right to data portability; the right to data portability allows users of the Service to obtain and reuse their Personal Information for their own purposes across different services; you may request us to transmit your Personal Information directly from our servers to another company’s servers and we will do so where it is technically feasible; 

  * the right to object (you have an absolute right to stop Personal Information being used for direct marketing, read our opt-out instructions below); you may express your objection verbally or in writing and we have a month to respond to any such objection; we might still continue processing your Personal Information if we are able to show that we have a compelling reason for doing so; 

  * the rights in relation to automated decision making and profiling. 

If you would like to exercise any of the above rights, please an email to: [support@bidsketch.com](mailto:support@bidsketch.com). 

### 7\. LOCATION OF SERVERS 

**_For users accessing the Service from EU_** : According to EU’s General Data Protection Regulation Personal Information must be erased immediately as long as such information is no longer needed for its original processing purpose, or the impacted person has withdrawn his/her consent and there is no other reason for justification, the impacted person has objected and there is no preferential justified reason for the processing, or erasure is required to fulfil a statutory obligation under the EU law or the right of the Member States. Therefore, if use the Service from one of the EU Member States, your Personal Information will be erased under all of the above circumstances. You may request us to erase your Personal Information verbally or in writing and we have a month to respond to any such request. 

**_For users accessing the Service from outside of EU_** : We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you with the Service. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements. 

### 8\. DO NOT TRACK DISCLOSURE 

We support Do Not Track ("DNT"). Do Not Track is a preference you can set in your web browser to inform websites that you do not want to be tracked. You can enable or disable Do Not Track by visiting the preferences or settings page of your web browser. 

### 9\. LINKS TO THIRD-PARTY WEB SITES 

Our Service may contain links to third-party web sites (through ads that they post in the Service) about products or services that are not owned or controlled by Bidsketch. 

Bidsketch has no control over, and assumes no responsibility for the content, privacy policies, or practices of any third-party web sites. We do not warrant the offerings of any of these entities/individuals or their websites. 

You acknowledge and agree that Bidsketch shall not be responsible or liable, directly or indirectly, for any damage or loss caused or alleged to be caused by or in connection with use of or reliance on any content, goods or services available on or through any such third-party web site. 

We strongly advise you to read the terms and conditions and privacy policies of any third-party web site that you access through link available in the Service. 

### 10\. CHILDREN'S PRIVACY 

Only persons age 18 or older have permission to access our Service. We do not knowingly collect Personal Information from anyone under the age of 18. If you are a parent or guardian and you learn that your child has provided us with Personal Information, please contact us immediate. If we become aware that we have collected Personal Information from anyone who is under 18 without verification of parental consent, we will take steps to remove that information from our servers. 

### 11\. COMPLIANCE WITH LAWS 

Our Privacy Policy complies with the strictest laws on handling of Personal Information. Such laws include: USA’s Children's Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA) and European Union’s General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR). 

### 12\. CHANGES TO PRIVACY POLICY 

We reserve the right, at our sole discretion, to modify or replace this Privacy Policy at any time. If a revision is material, we will provide at least 30 days notice prior to any new terms taking effect. What constitutes a material change will be determined at our sole discretion. 

By continuing to access or use our Service after any modifications become effective, you consent to all the practices described in the updated Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to the updated Privacy Policy, please terminate your account and stop using the Service. 

### 13\. CONTACT US 

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us. 

Earthlingsoft, LLC (DBA Bidsketch)   
12042 SE Sunnyside RD   
Portland, OR 97015   
Telephone: (503) 420-8266   
Email: [support@bidsketch.com](mailto:support@bidsketch.com)
